Office of the Registrar fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Office of the Registrar fonds
1965 - 2009, predominant 1965 - 1992
F-85
4.7 m of textual records 2 moving images
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Registrar's Office
The University Act provides for a registrar to "keep the records and perform the duties that the board or senate may require." It also states that the registrar "is the secretary of convocation, the senate and of each of the faculties, but has no right to vote as such." The Office of the Registrar is now part of the Office of Student Services.
Chief officers:
* Norman Barton, Registrar, 1965
* Lolita Wilson, Acting Registrar, 1965
* D.P. Robertson, Registrar, 1965-1968
* Harry M. Evans, Registrar, 1968-1984
* Ron Heath, Registrar, 1984-1996
* Ron Heath, Registrar / Dean of Student Serivces, 1996-2006
* Nello Angerilli (Associate Vice-President, Students and International), Acting Registrar, 2006-2007
* Kate Ross, Registrar, 2007-2013
* Tim Rahilly (Associate Vice-President, Students), Acting Registrar, 2013-2014
* Mark Walker, Registrar and Executive Director, Student Enrollment, 2014-2016
* Rummana Khan Hemani, Registrar and Executive Director, Student Enrollment, 2016-
published
Full
Revised
Title of the fonds is based on its provenance.
Digital materials (digitized copies of academic calendars) are in sub-series F-85-5-6. Digitized video is in F-85-5-1-0-12-1.
The fonds consists of five series. Series 1 contains material sent to Registrar Harry Evans from 1969-1970 regarding the crisis in the Department of Political Science Sociology, and Anthropology. Series 2 consists of five subject files concerning topics of interest to Registrars D.P. Robertson and Harry Evans. Series 3 contains records from the Academic Advice Centre. Series 4 contains records from Financial Aid. Series 5 contains publications produced by the Registrar's Office. Records include correspondence, press releases, newspapers, committee lists and terms of reference, minutes, reports, statistics, policies, organization charts, manuals, notes, and other documents. Also includes registrar's publications, such as admissions information booklets, timetables, and calendars.
Series 1 was kept in the order received. Series 2 was arranged by the archivist. Other series were arranged by the archivist or placed in chronological order.
Heath, Ron; Evans, Harry M.; Robertson, D. P.; Barton, Norman; Wilson, Lolita; Ross, Kate; Angerilli, Nello; Rahilly, Tim; Walker, Mark; Khan Hemani, Rummana
The buik of the records was transferred by the Registrar's Office to the University Records Centre around 1992. This material was appraised and scheduled by the Archives in 1994 and formally accessioned in 1998 and 1999. Record post-dating 1992 consists of publications (e.g. annual Calendar). This material is typically sent annually to the Archives as it is produced.
As of Nov 2017, ca. 2 m of additional material has been accessioned but not yet processed. Please consult the archivist for information about using these materials; restrictions may apply. Further accruals are expected.
The relationship between the Registrar's Office and the larger Student Services portfolio is complex and has taken varied forms over time. For the records of Student Services and its various sub-units, see fonds F-107, Student Services fonds.
The fonds includes records containing personal information. Access to these files is restricted in accordance with the provisions of British Columbia's Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act (RSBC 1996 c. 165). Files marked "pending review" must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review some files may be restricted in accordance with the FOI/POP Act. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
File list is available.
- Political Science, Sociology and Anthropology materials, 1969 - 1970; F-85-1; 7 cm of textual records
  published
  Records include correspondence, press releases, newspapers, and other materials.
  Records were kept in the order received.
  Department of Political Science, Sociology and Anthropology
  No further accruals to the series are expected.
  Please consult the inventories for the Swartz Collection, F 131 and the Archives PSA Collection, F150. For a view of the PSA crisis in a broader cotnext, see the following book by Michiel Horn: Academic Freedom in Canada: A History; University of Toronto Press, 1999.
  A file list is available.
  - PSA materials, vol. 1, 1969 - 1970; F-85-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - small 85-1)
    Textual records
    Pending review
  - PSA materials, vol. 2, 1969 - 1970; F-85-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - small 85-1)
  - PSA materials, vol. 3, 1969 - 1970; F-85-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - small 85-1)
- Subject files, 1967 - 1983; F-85-2; 7 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to topics of interest to the Registrar and the administration of the registrar's office. Examples of files nclude a history of the Registrar's Office and an external review.
  Records include committee lists and terms of reference, correspondence, minutes, reports, statistics and other documents.
  The records were arranged by the archivist.
  Further accruals to the series are expected.
  Access to files containing personal information may be restricted in accordance with the provisions of British Columbia's Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act (RSBC 1996 c. 165). Files marked "pending review" must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review some files may be restricted in accordance with the FOI/POP Act. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
  - Committees - Faculty of Science, 1967; F-85-2-0-0-1 (Archival box - small 85-2)
  - Honors Degree and First Class Standing requirements, 1967 - 1968; F-85-2-0-0-2 (Archival box - small 85-2)
  - History of Registrar's Office, 1968 - 1973; F-85-2-0-0-3 (Archival box - small 85-2)
  - External appraisal report of the Office of the Registrar, 1975; F-85-2-0-0-4 (Archival box - small 85-2)
  - Job split - Assistant to the Director, Admissions, 1977 - 1983; F-85-2-0-0-5 (Archival box - small 85-2)
- Academic Advice Centre files, 1971 - 1992; F-85-3; 19 cm of textual records
  This series consists of records relating to the organization, functions and activities of the Academic Advice Centre.
  Activities, events and topics documented include the history of the Centre, the deveopment of advising policies, and the appointment of student and faculty advisors.
  Records include correspondence, reports, statistics, minutes, policies, organization charts, manuals, lists, notes, and other documents.
  - Academic Advice Centre - development and history, vol. 1, 1972 - 1979; F-85-3-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 85-3)
  - Academic Advice Centre - development and history, vol. 2, 1972 - 1979; F-85-3-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 85-3)
  - Academic Advice Centre - meetings, 1981 - 1988; F-85-3-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 85-3)
  - Academic Advice Centre - Director's correspondence and reports, 1982 - 1992; F-85-3-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 85-3)
  - Academic Advice Centre - Advisors' appointment policy, 1974 - 1988; F-85-3-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 85-3)
  - Academic Advice Centre - advising information, 1978 - 1988; F-85-3-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 85-3)
  - Academic Advice Centre - sessional advising, 1989 - 1992; F-85-3-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 85-3)
  - Academic Advice Centre - advisors' manuals, 1982 - 1985; F-85-3-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 85-3)
  - Academic Advice Centre - advisors' manuals, 1986 - 1989; F-85-3-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 85-3)
  - Academic Advice Centre - brochures, 1971 - 1972; F-85-3-0-0-10 (Archival box - small 85-4)
  - Academic Advice Centre - faculty advisors active, 1971 - 1989; F-85-3-0-0-11 (Archival box - small 85-4)
  - Academic Advice Centre - faculty advisors semester lists, 1983 - 1989; F-85-3-0-0-12 (Archival box - small 85-4)
  - Academic Advice Centre - student advisors active, 1988 - 1992; F-85-3-0-0-13 (Archival box - small 85-4)
  - Academic Advice Centre - evening services, 1981 - 1984; F-85-3-0-0-14 (Archival box - small 85-4)
  - Academic Advice Centre - video tapes, 1982 - 1988; F-85-3-0-0-15 (Archival box - small 85-4)
- Financial Aid policy files, 1967 - 1985; F-85-4; 25 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to the delivery of scholarships, bursaries, and other forms of financial aid to undergraduate and graduate students.
  Records include policies, procedures, proposals, correspondence, lists of award candidates and winners, statistics, and other documents.
  Files were arranged by the archivist.
  See the subseries Senate Committee on Scholarships, Awards, and Bursaries,
  - Financial Aid - policy re graduate studies, 1970 - 1972; F-85-4-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 85-5)
  - Financial Aid - Canada Student loans, 1972; F-85-4-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 85-5)
  - Financial Aid - student financial assistance disbursement data, 1972 - 1973; F-85-4-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 85-5)
  - Financial Aid - university awards, 1972 - 1973; F-85-4-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 85-5)
  - Financial Aid - policy re SFU awards, 1972 - 1973; F-85-4-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 85-5)
  - Financial Aid - SFU entrance scholarships, 1972 - 1973; F-85-4-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 85-5)
  - Financial Aid - policy re SFU open scholarships, 1972 - 1973; F-85-4-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 85-5)
  - Financial Aid - SFU statistics, 1967 - 1972; F-85-4-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 85-5)
  - Financial Aid - policy re Resources Office, 1971 - 1972; F-85-4-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 85-5)
  - Financial Aid - part time student, 1972 - 1973; F-85-4-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 85-5)
  - Financial Aid - packaging concept, 1972 - 1973; F-85-4-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 85-5)
  - Financial Aid - policy re Recreation department, 1971 - 1972; F-85-4-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 85-6)
  - Financial Aid - policy re BC Government scholarships, 1972 - 1974; F-85-4-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 85-6)
  - Financial Aid - policy re Bursar's office, 1969 - 1976; F-85-4-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 85-6)
  - Financial Aid - graduate awards, vol. 1, 1980 - 1985; F-85-4-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 85-6)
  - Financial Aid - graduate awards, vol. 2, 1980 - 1985; F-85-4-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 85-6)
  - Financial Aid - summary report awards, 1975; F-85-4-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 85-6)
  - Financial Aid - salary administration for APSA staff, 1983; F-85-4-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 85-6)
- Publications, 1965 - 2008; F-85-5; 4.13 m of textual records 732.52 GB of textual records (tiff, pdf): digitized copies 2 moving images
  Series consists of publications produced by the Office of the Registrar.
  The arrangement was provided by the archivist.
  The files are open with no restrictions.
  Digital materials (digitized copies of academic calendars) are in sub-series F-85-5-6. Digitized video is in F-85-5-1-0-12.
  - Admissions publications, 1966 - 1999; F-85-5-1; 24 cm of textual records 2 moving images
    Sub-series consists of records relating to the admission of students to SFU. Records include admission brochures and documents describing admission requirements.
    - Admissions publications—general, 1966 - 1970; F-85-5-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 85-7)
      Open
    - Report—Admission Requirements for BC Students, 1967; F-85-5-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 85-7)
    - Admissions and Standings—A Suggested Policy by John Ellis, 1969; F-85-5-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 85-7)
    - BC Regional College Transfer Guides, 1969 - 1988; F-85-5-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 85-7)
    - Admissions publications—general, 1971; F-85-5-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 85-7)
    - Admissions publications—general, 1971 - 1978; F-85-5-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 85-7)
    - SFU admissions newsletter for high school counselors and students, 1971 - 1979; F-85-5-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 85-8)
    - Admissions publications -- general, 1979; F-85-5-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 85-8)
    - Admissions publications -- general, 1980; F-85-5-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 85-8)
    - Admissions publications -- general, 1981; F-85-5-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 85-8)
    - Admissions publications -- general, 1982; F-85-5-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 85-8)
    - Admissions publications -- general, 1983; F-85-5-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 85-8)
      - SFU Liaison Program, September 6, 1983; 1983; F-85-5-1-0-12-1; 2 film reels 2 videocassettes 2 .mov files (Videocassette: 3/4&quot; umatic OBJ-2224, Videocassette: 3/4&quot; umatic OBJ-2225, Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2181, Film reel: 16mm OBJ-2182)
        Short marketing/promotion piece about SFU created for the Office of Admissions. General information about SFU: "the people, the location, the faculty and the buildings."
        Seahawk Communications; Moving images; Records in electronic form (digitized)
        .mov files are also available in .mp4 and .mkv formats.
        - OBJ-2224.mov
        - OBJ-2225.mov
    - Admissions publications -- general, 1984; F-85-5-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 85-8)
    - Admissions publications -- general, 1985; F-85-5-1-0-14 (Archival box - standard 85-8)
    - Admissions publications -- general, 1987; F-85-5-1-0-15 (Archival box - standard 85-8)
    - Admissions publications -- general, 1988; F-85-5-1-0-16 (Archival box - standard 85-8)
    - Admissions publications -- general, 1990; F-85-5-1-0-17 (Archival box - standard 85-8)
    - Admissions publications -- general, 1993; F-85-5-1-0-18 (Archival box - standard 85-8)
    - Admissions publications -- general, 1997; F-85-5-1-0-19 (Archival box - standard 85-8)
    - Admissions publications -- general, 1999; F-85-5-1-0-20 (Archival box - standard 85-8)
  - Pre-registration handbooks and timetables, 1970 - 2007; F-85-5-2; 2.41 m of textual records
    Sub-series consists of pre-registration handbooks, timetables, and registration instructions.
    Files are arranged chronologically.
    - Course guide and schedule, 1970 - 1971; F-85-5-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 85-8)
    - Course offerings, 1972 - 1976; F-85-5-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 85-8)
    - Course offerings, 1977 - 1983; F-85-5-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 85-9)
    - Pre-registration handbook and timetable, 1972; F-85-5-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 85-9)
    - Pre-registration handbook and timetable, 1973; F-85-5-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 85-9)
    - Pre-registration handbook and timetable, 1974; F-85-5-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 85-9)
    - Pre-registration handbook and timetable, 1975; F-85-5-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 85-9)
    - Pre-registration handbook and timetable, 1976; F-85-5-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 85-9)
    - Pre-registration handbook and timetable, 1977; F-85-5-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 85-9)
    - Pre-registration handbook and timetable, 1978; F-85-5-2-0-10 (Archival box - standard 85-9)
    - Pre-registration handbook and timetable, 1979; F-85-5-2-0-11 (Archival box - standard 85-9)
    - Pre-registration handbook and timetable, 1980; F-85-5-2-0-12 (Archival box - standard 85-10)
    - Pre-registration handbook and timetable, 1981; F-85-5-2-0-13 (Archival box - standard 85-10)
    - Pre-registration handbook and timetable, 1982; F-85-5-2-0-14 (Archival box - standard 85-10)
    - Pre-registration handbook and timetable, 1983; F-85-5-2-0-15 (Archival box - standard 85-10)
    - Pre-registration handbook and timetable, 1984; F-85-5-2-0-16 (Archival box - standard 85-10)
    - Pre-registration handbook and timetable 1986-3, F-85-5-2-0-17 (Archival box - standard 85-10)
    - Course timetable report 1987-1, F-85-5-2-0-18 (Archival box - standard 85-11)
    - Course timetable report 1987-2, F-85-5-2-0-19 (Archival box - standard 85-11)
    - Course timetable report 1987-3, F-85-5-2-0-20 (Archival box - standard 85-11)
    - Course timetable report 1988-3, F-85-5-2-0-21 (Archival box - standard 85-11)
    - Course timetable report 1989-1, F-85-5-2-0-22 (Archival box - standard 85-11)
    - Course timetable report 1989-2, F-85-5-2-0-23 (Archival box - standard 85-12)
    - Course timetable report 1989-3, F-85-5-2-0-24 (Archival box - standard 85-12)
    - Course timetable report 1990-1, F-85-5-2-0-25 (Archival box - standard 85-12)
    - Course timetable report 1990-2, F-85-5-2-0-26 (Archival box - standard 85-12)
    - Course timetable report 1990-3, F-85-5-2-0-27 (Archival box - standard 85-12)
    - Course timetable report 1991-1, F-85-5-2-0-28 (Archival box - standard 85-13)
    - Course timetable report 1991-2, F-85-5-2-0-29 (Archival box - standard 85-13)
    - Course timetable report 1991-3, F-85-5-2-0-30 (Archival box - standard 85-13)
    - Course timetable report 1992-1, F-85-5-2-0-31 (Archival box - standard 85-14)
    - Course timetable report 1992-2, F-85-5-2-0-32 (Archival box - standard 85-14)
    - Course timetable report 1992-3, F-85-5-2-0-33 (Archival box - standard 85-14)
    - Course timetable report 1993-1, F-85-5-2-0-34 (Archival box - standard 85-15)
    - Course timetable report 1993-2, F-85-5-2-0-35 (Archival box - standard 85-15)
    - Course timetable report 1993-3, F-85-5-2-0-36 (Archival box - standard 85-15)
    - Course timetable report 1994-1, F-85-5-2-0-37 (Archival box - standard 85-16)
    - Course timetable report 1994-2, F-85-5-2-0-38 (Archival box - standard 85-16)
    - Course timetable report 1994-3, F-85-5-2-0-39 (Archival box - standard 85-16)
    - Course timetable report 1995-1, F-85-5-2-0-40 (Archival box - standard 85-17)
    - Course timetable report 1995-2, F-85-5-2-0-41 (Archival box - standard 85-17)
    - Course timetable report 1996-1, F-85-5-2-0-42 (Archival box - standard 85-18)
    - Course timetable report 1996-2, F-85-5-2-0-43 (Archival box - standard 85-18)
    - Course timetable report 1996-3, F-85-5-2-0-44 (Archival box - standard 85-18)
    - Course timetable report 1997-1, F-85-5-2-0-45 (Archival box - standard 85-19)
    - Course timetable report 1997-2, F-85-5-2-0-46 (Archival box - standard 85-19)
    - Course timetable report 1997-3, F-85-5-2-0-47 (Archival box - standard 85-19)
    - Course timetable report 1998-1, F-85-5-2-0-48 (Archival box - standard 85-20)
    - Course timetable report 1998-2, F-85-5-2-0-49 (Archival box - standard 85-20)
    - Course timetable report 1998-3, F-85-5-2-0-50 (Archival box - standard 85-20)
    - Course timetable report 1999-1, F-85-5-2-0-51 (Archival box - standard 85-21)
    - Course timetable report 1999-2, F-85-5-2-0-52 (Archival box - standard 85-21)
    - Course timetable report 1999-3, F-85-5-2-0-53 (Archival box - standard 85-21)
    - Course timetable report 2000-1, F-85-5-2-0-54 (Archival box - standard 85-22)
    - Course timetable report 2000-2, F-85-5-2-0-55 (Archival box - standard 85-22)
    - Course timetable report 2000-3, F-85-5-2-0-56 (Archival box - standard 85-22)
    - Course timetable report 2001-1, F-85-5-2-0-57 (Archival box - standard 85-23)
    - Course timetable report 2001-2, F-85-5-2-0-58 (Archival box - standard 85-23)
    - Course timetable report 2001-3, F-85-5-2-0-59 (Archival box - standard 85-23)
    - Course timetable report 2002-1, F-85-5-2-0-60 (Archival box - standard 85-24)
    - Course timetable report 2002-2, F-85-5-2-0-61 (Archival box - standard 85-24)
    - Course timetable report 2002-3, F-85-5-2-0-62 (Archival box - standard 85-24)
    - Course timetable report 2003-1, vol. 1, F-85-5-2-0-63 (Archival box - standard 85-25)
    - Course timetable report 2003-1, vol. 2, F-85-5-2-0-64 (Archival box - standard 85-25)
    - Course timetable report 2003-2, F-85-5-2-0-65 (Archival box - standard 85-25)
    - Course timetable report 2003-3, F-85-5-2-0-66 (Archival box - standard 85-37)
    - Course timetable report 2004-1, F-85-5-2-0-67 (Archival box - standard 85-37)
    - Course timetable report 2004-2, F-85-5-2-0-68 (Archival box - standard 85-37)
    - Course timetable report 2004-3, F-85-5-2-0-69 (Archival box - standard 85-37)
    - Course timetable report 2005-1, F-85-5-2-0-70 (Archival box - standard 85-38)
    - Course timetable and exam schedule 2005-2,3, F-85-5-2-0-71 (Archival box - standard 85-38)
    - Course timetable and exam schedule 2006, F-85-5-2-0-72 (Archival box - standard 85-38)
    - Course timetable and exam schedule 2007, F-85-5-2-0-73 (Archival box - standard 85-38)
  - Calendars [Superseded / Obsoleted], F-85-5-3
    This sub-series has been retired. It is superseded by sub-series F-85-5-6, Academic calendars.
  - Harbour Centre catalogues, 1992 - 2003; F-85-5-4; 9 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of catalogues for the Harbour Centre campus of SFU.
    - Calendars -- Harbour Centre, 1992 - 1995; F-85-5-4-0-1 (Archival box - standard 85-36)
    - Calendars -- Harbour Centre, 1996 - 1999; F-85-5-4-0-2 (Archival box - standard 85-36)
    - Calendars -- Harbour Centre, 2000 - 2003; F-85-5-4-0-3 (Archival box - standard 85-36)
  - Registrar's Office newsletters, 1985 - 1995; F-85-5-5; 3 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of internal newsletters published by the Registrar's Office.
    - Registrar's Office newsletters, 1985 - 1995; F-85-5-5-0-1 (Archival box - standard 85-36)
  - Academic calendars, 2016; 1965-2010; F-85-5-6; 1.75 m of textual records: originals 732.52 GB of textual records (tiff, pdf): digitized copies
    Sub-series consists of academic calendars published in print form by the university for each academic year. The sub-series represents a complete run of all print editions, from SFU's first academic year (1965-66) to the final year for which a print edition was produced (2009-10).
    From 1965-66 until 1981-82, SFU produced separate calendars for undergraduate and graduate studies. The format changed in 1982-83, with a single calendar covering both undergraduate and graduate programs. The calendar continued in this format until 2010, when the university discontinued the print edition. Since that time, SFU maintains the calendar as a web-based product only. At the present time of writing (October 2017), the digital records for the calendar from 2010 onwards remain in the custody and control of Registrar's Office / Student Services.
    In 2015, the Archives digitized a complete set of the calendars. This sub-series includes both the print editions and digitized copies.
    The sub-series is arranged into files, with one file for each academic year. Each calendar is registered as an item of that file. Up until 1981-82, there were separate calendars for undergraduate and graduate studies, and each is treated as an item of the same file. Starting in 1982-83 only a single calendar was produced, so files from this date on contain only a single item.
    Note that this sub-series was created in 2017. It replaces the previous sub-series F-85-5-3, which had arranged the print editions into a number of files, each file containing a number of calendars. The new arrangement was intended to facilitate access to the digitized copies.
    Textual records; Records in electronic form (digitized)